# **Irene Chakraborty**

Business System Analyst at Bank of the West

### Summary

# Over Ten Years of experience working in information technology as senior developer, software analyst, sustems and business analyst # Experience across various business domains - Banking & Financial Services, Insurance, Manufacturing and Retail domains. # Expertise working with Business and IT divisions in requirements gathering, requirement analysis, estimation, design, UAT and implementation on development, maintenance and support # Knowledge of Agile, Waterfall and Rational Unified processing software development methodologies # Experience in Use Case point, Function point and Complexity point estimation techniques

## Experience

#### Business System Analyst at Bank of the West

January 2015 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Intermediate Holding Company Program; Lead BA on IHC risk reporting for financial and non-financial risk - credit, counterparty, operational, compliance, model etc. Knowledge on Moody's Risk Foundation and Risk Authority modules for reporting. Understanding of Treasury Reports - LCR calculation (liquidity coverage ratio) and GL reconciliation. Technically well versed with SQL, Toad for Oracle, HP Quality Center.

#### **Business System Analyst at Cognizant Technology Solutions**

March 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 10 months)

#### Senior Technical Lead at Cognizant Technology Solutions

June 2010 - March 2012 (1 year 10 months)

#### System Analyst at JPMorgan Chase

2010 - 2012 (2 years)

## Skills & Expertise

**XML** 

**SDLC** 

**SQL** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Business Analysis** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

**User Acceptance Testing** 

**Solution Architecture** 

Oracle Requirements Gathering Visio Data Warehousing Analysis

## Education

**Vellore Institute of Technology** 

B.Tech, 2001 - 2005

**Notre Dame Academy** 

# **Irene Chakraborty**

Business System Analyst at Bank of the West



Contact Irene on LinkedIn